Register of the John Davenport Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John A. Davenport papers,
1919-1987
99018
Davenport, John, 1904-1987
60 manuscript boxes (25.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, and printed matter, relating to economic conditions in the United States, laissez-faire and conservative political thought, right-to-work issues, and political conditions in southern Africa, especially Zimbabwe and South Africa.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Biographical Note
1904, September 11 Born, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
1926 Graduated from Yale University
1927-1930 Reporter, New York World
1937-1949 Member of staff, Fortune magazine
1941-1949 Member, Board of Editors, Fortune magazine
1945 Author, The Lives of Winston Churchill
1949-1954 Managing editor, Barron's weekly
1954-1969 Assistant managing editor, Fortune magazine
1964 Author, The U.S. Economy
1987 June Died, Red Bank, New Jersey
Scope and Content Note
The papers of John Davenport were acquired by the Hoover Institution from his widow, Marie Davenport, in 1999. They relate mainly to his career as economist, author, and journalist from 1927 until his death in 1987. His position as editor at Barron's weekly and Fortune provided a fruitful venue for his widely read writings.
The bulk of the collection consists of holographs, typescripts, and printed copies of these writings. They relate mainly to American and international economic policy, economic planning, the gold standard, labor unions, labor law, Rhodesia, South Africa, and welfare economics. Included are many speeches on the same topics.
Of significant importance is Davenport's correspondence with prominent economists and politicians, such as Milton Friedman, Friedrich von Hayek, Jesse Helms, Henry Kissinger, and Karl von Wiegand, which reflects his life-long interest in the economy and political life of the United States.
The Mont Pèlerin Society, the National Right to Work Committee, and the National Right to Work Legal Defense Committee files are smaller but equally important parts of the collection. The Mont Pèlerin Society file consists of materials on meetings, newsletters, and Davenport's speeches and writings as a member of the Society. The National Right to Work Committee and the National Right to Work Legal Defense Committee files consist of materials relating to the labor question in the United States and reflect Davenport's contribution to both organizations.
Of special note in the Subject File is material relating to Rhodesia and South Africa. The Rhodesian materials reflect the economic and political conditions before the advent of Zimbabwe. The South African materials provide an especially interesting source for the study of economic policy and apartheid.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Laissez-faire.; Open and closed shop--United States.; Conservatism.; Africa, Southern.; Zimbabwe--History--1965-1980.; South Africa--History--1961-; United States--Politics and government.; Zimbabwe.; South Africa.; Africa.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-
Occupations
Journalists.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1950-1985. (Box 1)
  Address books, family correspondence, mailing lists, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
- Correspondence File, 1919-1986. (Box 1-5)
  Letters sent and received, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- Speeches and Writings, 1941-1986. (Box 5-23)
  Handwritten and typewritten drafts, typescripts, manuscripts, speech transcripts, printed copies, notes and related materials, arranged chronologically by title.
- Mont Pelerin Society File, 1947-1986. (Box 23-24)
  Correspondence, minutes of meetings, newsletters, and speeches and writings by J. Davenport, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
- National Right to Work Legal Defense Foundation File, 1969-1987. (Box 24-26)
  Correspondence, reports, financial information, news releases and other material relating to the operations of the National Right to Work Legal Defense Foundation, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- National Right to Work Committee File, 1971-1987. (Box 27-28)
  Correspondence, news releases, newsletters, and printed matter relating to operations of the National Right to Work Committee, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Subject File, 1965-1987. (Box 28-58)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter and other material, collected by J. Davenport and relating to various subjects, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Writings by Others, 1961-1980. (Box 58-60)
  Articles by various individuals, arranged alphabetically by name of author.
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1950-1985 (Box 1)
  - Address books (Folder 1: 1)
  - Family correspondence
    - Davenport, Marie, 1985 (Folder 1: 2)
    - Davenport, Sharon, n.d. (Folder 1: 3)
  - Mailing lists (Folder 1: 4)
  - Miscellany (Folder 1: 5)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1919-1986
  - General
    - Letters of thanks for speaking engagements, 1964 (Folder 1: 6)
    - Letters relating to South Africa anti-apartheid legislation in the United States, 1985-1986 (Folder 1: 7)
    - Letters to editors of various publications, 1956-1986 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Unidentified (Folder 1: 9)
  - American Economic Foundation, 1979-1982 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Antonio, Iris, 1947 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Aschan, David, 1980 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Associated Industries of Cleveland, 1964 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Association d'Etudes pour l'Expansion de l'Economie, 1954 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Banks, Louis, 1965-1968 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Bankston, L. W., 1982 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Bartley, Robert, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Baxter, 1981 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Bethlehem Steel Company, 1952-1954 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Black, D. J., 1977 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Boeschenstein, Harold, 1954 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Bozell, Brent, 1969 (Folder 2: 6)
  - British Supply Council in North America, 1943 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Brooke, P. L., Mrs., 1968 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Brooke, S. W., 1982 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Brown, Benjamin, 1977 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Brozen, Yale, 1961-1963 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Brugger, James R., 1954 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1977 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Buchman, Pat, 1986 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Buckley, James, 1971, 1981 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Buckley, William F., 1981-1983 (Folder 2: 16)
  - Bullock, Hugh, 1954 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Bunche, Mr., 1963 (Folder 2: 18)
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1948 (Folder 2: 19)
  - Burgess, W. Randolph, 1948-1954 (Folder 2: 20)
  - Burns, John W., 1980 (Folder 2: 21)
  - Cairns, J. P., 1964-1965 (Folder 2: 22)
  - Campbell, W. Glenn, n.d. (Folder 2: 23)
  - Canadian Manufacturers Association, 1964 (Folder 2: 24)
  - Carlen, Robert, 1985 (Folder 2: 25)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1979 (Folder 2: 26)
  - Carter, Hodding, 1977-1978 (Folder 2: 27)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1977-1979 (Folder 2: 28)
  - Case, Clifford P., 1977-1978 (Folder 2: 29)
  - CBS News, 1963 (Folder 2: 30)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1981 (Folder 2: 31)
  - Consumer Alert, 1985 (Folder 2: 32)
  - Cooney, Joan Ganz, 1964 (Folder 2: 33)
  - Cornwell, Geoffrey, 1980 (Folder 2: 34)
  - Coster, Charles H., 1961 (Folder 2: 35)
  - Cotton, Nan Hauser, 1974 (Folder 2: 36)
  - Currier, Elizabeth, 1978, 1981 (Folder 2: 37)
  - Deitz, James E., 1974 (Folder 2: 38)
  - De Luca, Peter, 1980 (Folder 2: 39)
  - Di Perna, Anthony, 1985 (Folder 2: 40)
  - Director, Aaron, 1955 (Folder 2: 41)
  - Di Verne, Tony, 1979 (Folder 2: 42)
  - Dole, Bob, 1985 (Folder 2: 43)
  - Donovan, Hedley, 1954, 1958, 1965-1970, 1982 (Folder 2: 44)
  - Doolan, Robert, 1971 (Folder 2: 45)
  - Downs, Kenneth T., 1963 (Folder 2: 46)
  - Drysdale, R. M., 1982 (Folder 2: 47)
  - Durbrow, Elbridge, 1981 (Folder 2: 48)
  - Eberstadt, Ferdinand, 1946 (Folder 2: 49)
  - Eckerman, Dwight, 1954 (Folder 2: 50)
  - The Economist (London), 1954 (Folder 2: 51)
  - Economists National Committee on Monetary Policy, 1960 (Folder 2: 52)
  - Exter, John, 1982 (Folder 2: 53)
  - Farrar, Margaret, n.d. (Folder 2: 54)
  - Federal Reserve System. Board of Governors, 1980 (Folder 2: 55)
  - Feulner, Edwin J., 1982 (Folder 2: 56)
  - Flanders, Ralph, 1946 (Folder 2: 57)
  - Foreign Affairs, 1977 (Folder 2: 58)
  - Forest, P., n.d. (Folder 2: 59)
  - Forrestal, James V., 1948-1949 (Folder 2: 60)
  - Forrestal, Mr., 1946 (Folder 2: 61)
  - Fortune, 1965-1983 (Folder 2: 62)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, 1982-1984 (Folder 2: 63)
  - Foundation for Free Enterprise, 1979-1984 (Folder 2: 64)
  - Frankel, S. F., 1974 (Folder 2: 65)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1975-1984 (Folder 2: 66)
  - Garn, E. J., 1986-1987 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Garrett, Paul, 1948 (Folder 3: 2)
  - General Electric, 1984 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Gethman, Kenneth, 1987 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Giamatti, A. Bartlett, 1979 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Gibson, Jonathan, 1975 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Gilder, Mr., 1981 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Gold, Mr., 1979 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Goldberg, Todd, n.d. (Folder 3: 9)
  - Goodrich, Pierre, 1973 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Gottfried, Paul, 1975 (Folder 3: 11)
  - Grace, J. Peter, 1979-1983 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Grant, James, 1982, 1983 (Folder 3: 13)
  - Grinaker, O. W., 1977 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Gruenther, Alfred, 1954 (Folder 3: 15)
  - Haig, Alexander, 1981 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Haight, George W., 1971 (Folder 3: 17)
  - Hall, Lillian M., 1977 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Hare, Andrew E., 1983-1984 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Harper's, 1980 (Folder 3: 20)
  - Harriman, Mr., 1946 (Folder 3: 21)
  - Hartwell, R. Max, 1985 (Folder 3: 22)
  - Hawaii Employers Council, 1966 (Folder 3: 23)
  - Hayek, Friedrick A. von, 1948-1970 (Folder 3: 24)
  - Hazlitt, Henry, 1954 (Folder 3: 25)
  - Heilperin, Michael A., 1965 (Folder 3: 26)
  - Heinz, John, 1979 (Folder 3: 27)
  - Helms, Jesse, 1982, 1985 (Folder 3: 28)
  - Heritage Foundation, 1981-1984 (Folder 3: 29)
  - High, Jack, 1981 (Folder 3: 30)
  - Hillsdale College, Center for Constructive Alternatives, 1980 (Folder 3: 31)
  - Hoffman, Beth, 1982 (Folder 3: 32)
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 1947, 1957 (Folder 3: 33)
  - Horwood, Owen, 1977, 1983 (Folder 3: 34)
  - Howard, Dr., n.d. (Folder 3: 35)
  - Human Events, 1982 (Folder 3: 36)
  - Hutt, W. H., 1974, 1980 (Folder 3: 37)
  - Industrial Management Club of Utica, New York, 1965 (Folder 3: 38)
  - Information Service of South Africa, 1972 (Folder 3: 39)
  - Intercollegiate Review, n.d. (Folder 3: 40)
  - Intercollegiate Studies Institute, 1983-1986 (Folder 3: 41)
  - International Center for Economic Policy Studies, 1981 (Folder 3: 42)
  - International Monetary Fund, 1965 (Folder 3: 43)
  - Janney Montgomery Scott, Inc., 1983 (Folder 3: 44)
  - Johnson, Norris O., 1954 (Folder 3: 45)
  - Jones, Homer, 1980 (Folder 3: 46)
  - Kahn, Alfred E., 1983 (Folder 3: 47)
  - Kemmerer, Donald L., 1977 (Folder 3: 48)
  - Kemp, Jack, 1983 (Folder 3: 49)
  - Kilgore, Bernard, 1951-1954 (Folder 3: 50)
  - Kintner, William R., 1979-1985 (Folder 3: 51)
  - Kirkpatrick, Jeane, 1981 (Folder 3: 52)
  - Kirzner, Israel, 1975 (Folder 3: 53)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1977-1978 (Folder 3: 54)
  - Knight, Frank H., 1945 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Labor Policy Association, 1972 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Laffer, Arthur B., 1976 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Langenberg, H. F., 1986 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Larson, Reed, 1977-1988 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Law, Helen, 1974 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Leach, H. A., 1983 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Leffingwell, R. C., 1948 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Lehrman, Lew, n.d. (Folder 4: 9)
  - Lehrman Institute, 1981-1982 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Leigh Bureau, 1981 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1948-1954 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Lipsett, Don, 1976, 1980 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Loeb, Rhoades and Company, 1971 (Folder 4: 14)
  - Lombard, Laurence, 1954 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Long, Clarence D., 1961 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Lubar, R., 1969 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Luce, Henry, 1944-1961 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Lugar, Richard C., 1986 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Luitweiler, J. C., 1977 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Machinery and Allied Products Institute, 1960 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1965 (Folder 4: 22)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, n.d. (Folder 4: 23)
  - MacNeil/Lehrer Newshour, 1985 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Martelli, Dominic, 1982 (Folder 4: 25)
  - Mayer, Ferdinand, 1954 (Folder 4: 26)
  - Mayer, Larry, n.d. (Folder 4: 27)
  - Meaney, George, 1978 (Folder 4: 28)
  - Meltzer, Allan H., 1981-1982 (Folder 4: 29)
  - Merchants and Manufacturers Association, 1962 (Folder 4: 30)
  - Merritt, Theodore C., 1978 (Folder 4: 31)
  - Middendorf, J. William, II, 1982 (Folder 4: 32)
  - Moor, Arthur Prichard, 1974 (Folder 4: 33)
  - Morley, Felix, 1954-1979 (Folder 4: 34)
  - Mothershead, John L., 1963 (Folder 4: 35)
  - Mudge, Mr., n.d. (Folder 4: 36)
  - Mulloy, John, 1972 (Folder 4: 37)
  - Murphy, Charles, 1948 (Folder 4: 38)
  - Nash, Verne, 1964 (Folder 4: 39)
  - National Review, 1982-1983 (Folder 4: 40)
  - Neel, Samuel E., 1957 (Folder 4: 41)
  - New York Chamber of Commerce, 1965 (Folder 4: 42)
  - New York Times, 1972-1981 (Folder 4: 43)
  - Niemeyer, Gerhart, 1977 (Folder 4: 44)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1954 (Folder 4: 45)
  - Norton-Taylor, Duncan, 1963, 1965 (Folder 4: 46)
  - Nymeyer, Frederick, 1970 (Folder 4: 47)
  - O'Connell, Frank, 1982 (Folder 4: 48)
  - Parker, Sanford, 1963 (Folder 4: 49)
  - Parris, Charles W., 1980 (Folder 4: 50)
  - Pearson, George, 1977 (Folder 4: 51)
  - Peters, Ron W., 1977 (Folder 4: 52)
  - Peterson, William H., 1983 (Folder 4: 53)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1980 (Folder 4: 54)
  - The Public Interest, 1978 (Folder 4: 55)
  - Readers Digest, 1983 (Folder 4: 56)
  - Reagan, Ronald and Nancy, 1981 (Folder 4: 57)
  - Regnery, Henry, 1982 (Folder 4: 58)
  - Review (St. Louis), 1983 (Folder 4: 59)
  - Rhodesian Information Office, Washington, D.C., 1977-1978 (Folder 4: 60)
  - Rice, Charles E., 1965 (Folder 4: 61)
  - Roberts, K. Clayton, 1984, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Roche, George, 1980, 1982 (Folder 5: 2)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1946 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1948 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Rostow, Eugene V., 1969-1979 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Rotan Mosle, Inc., 1981 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Rueff, Jacques, 1961 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Rupert, Anton, 1976-1977 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Scarfe, Dr., 1981 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Schmidt, Emerson, 1971-1973 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Scranton, William W., 1970 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Segermark, Howard, 1982 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Seldner, Joseph, 1981 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Semple, Robert, 1986-1987 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Shenfield, Arthur, 1984 (Folder 5: 15)
  - Sherer, Albert W., 1976 (Folder 5: 16)
  - Slichter, Sumner, 1954 (Folder 5: 17)
  - Smith, Don H., 1981 (Folder 5: 18)
  - Smith, Edgar W., 1948 (Folder 5: 19)
  - Smith, Mrs., n.d. (Folder 5: 20)
  - Stebbins, Theodore E., Jr., 1982 (Folder 5: 21)
  - Sternlight, Peter D., 1981 (Folder 5: 22)
  - Stoddard, Carlos F., 1981 (Folder 5: 23)
  - Stuart, Alex J., 1983 (Folder 5: 24)
  - Taube, John A., 1983 (Folder 5: 25)
  - Tax Foundation, 1981 (Folder 5: 26)
  - Thatcher School, 1919 (Folder 5: 27)
  - Thayer, Frederick, n.d. (Folder 5: 28)
  - Time, 1982 (Folder 5: 29)
  - Time-Life International, 1954 (Folder 5: 30)
  - Toby, Phineas, 1972 (Folder 5: 31)
  - Tonsor, Stephen, 1970 (Folder 5: 32)
  - United States. Department of State. Office of Southern African Affairs, 1981 (Folder 5: 33)
  - United States. Office of Personnel Management, n.d. (Folder 5: 34)
  - University of Western Ontario, 1983 (Folder 5: 35)
  - Vance, Cyrus, 1976-1977 (Folder 5: 36)
  - Von der Heydt, Peter, 1982 (Folder 5: 37)
  - Von Wiegand, Karl, n.d. (Folder 5: 38)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1983 (Folder 5: 39)
  - Wardell, Elsa, 1971 (Folder 5: 40)
  - Ware, Richard A., 1981 (Folder 5: 41)
  - The Washington Post, 1964 (Folder 5: 42)
  - Wasson, Gordon, 1948 (Folder 5: 43)
  - Ways, Max, 1963 (Folder 5: 44)
  - White, James N., 1954 (Folder 5: 45)
  - Whitney, Simon W., 1947-1948 (Folder 5: 46)
  - Whittingham, Charles A., 1980 (Folder 5: 47)
  - Winton, Haynes, 1959 (Folder 5: 48)
  - Yakima Chief Ranch, 1972 (Folder 5: 49)
  - Yale University, School of Medecine, 1981 (Folder 5: 50)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1941-1986., See also MONT PELERIN SOCIETY FILE/Speeches and writings by J. Davenport
  - General
    - Drafts and notes
      - General (Folder 5: 51-52)
      - General (Box-folder 6: 1-7)
      - General (Box-folder 7: 1-6)
      - General (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - Budget - United States (Folder 8: 2-3)
      - Economic planning (Folder 8: 4)
      - Federal Reserve System (U.S.) (Folder 8: 5)
      - Fortune magazine (Folder 8: 6-7)
      - Gold standard (Folder 8: 8-9)
      - Goldwater, Barry (Folder 8: 10)
      - Labor and laboring classes - United States (Folder 8: 11)
      - Labor law - United States (Folder 8: 12)
      - Mental health, international (Folder 8: 13)
      - Mental health services - United States (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Monetary policy - United States (Folder 9: 2-3)
      - Psychiatry (Folder 9: 4)
      - Rhodesia (Folder 9: 5-7)
      - Segregation - United States (Folder 9: 8)
      - South Africa (Box-folder 10: 1-6)
      - South Africa (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - Southwest Africa (Folder 11: 2)
      - Sternlight, Peter (Folder 11: 3)
      - Stigler, George (Folder 11: 4)
      - Welfare economics (Folder 11: 5)
    - Galley proofs (Folder 11: 6)
    - Lecture notes (Folder 11: 7)
    - Notebooks
      - General (Folder 11: 8)
      - General (Box-folder 12: 1-4)
      - General (Box-folder 13: 1-5)
      - General (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
      - ISI Summer Institute, 1977 August (Folder 14: 3)
      - Rhodesia (Folder 14: 4)
      - South Africa (Folder 14: 5)
      - Southwest Africa (Folder 14: 6)
  - The Acids of Modernity," lecture notes, n.d. (Folder 14: 7)
    Typescript
  - "The American Dollar," n.d. (Folder 14: 8)
  - "The American Position," n.d. (Folder 14: 9)
  - "The Anti-Apartheid Threat," n.d. (Folder 14: 10)
    Printed copy
  - "Anton Gilbert," n.d. (Folder 14: 11)
  - "Banking," n.d. (Folder 14: 12)
  - "Banking and Inflation," n.d. (Box-folder 15: 1)
    Notes, holographs, typescript
  - "Barron's in Perspective," n.d. (Folder 15: 2)
  - "Beyond the Free Market," n.d. (Folder 15: 3)
  - "Brace Up America," n.d. (Folder 15: 4)
  - "The Brooding Presence," n.d. (Folder 15: 5)
  - "Budget," n.d. (Folder 15: 6)
  - "Can It Be That Simple," n.d. (Folder 15: 7)
    Typescript with annotations
  - "The Challenge," n.d. (Folder 15: 8)
  - "The Challenge of Union Power," n.d. (Folder 15: 9)
  - "The Challenge of Unionism," n.d. (Folder 15: 10)
  - "Collective Bargaining: A No Man's Land," n.d. (Folder 15: 11)
  - "Collective Bargaining Revisited," n.d. (Folder 15: 12)
  - "Coming Clean on South Africa," n.d. (Folder 15: 13)
  - "Comment on Mrs. Letwin's Essay," n.d. (Folder 15: 14)
  - "Crime and Punishment," n.d. (Folder 15: 15)
  - "Defiance of the Law," n.d. (Folder 15: 16)
  - "The Desk," n.d. (Folder 15: 17)
  - "Dissent," n.d. (Folder 15: 18)
  - "An English Summer," n.d. (Folder 15: 19)
  - "The Fed and the Figures: An Unhappy Marriage," n.d. (Folder 15: 20)
  - "Fortune: Lives of the Poets," n.d. (Folder 15: 21)
  - "From the Common Law to the Common Hold-Up," n.d. (Folder 15: 22)
  - "The Future of Collective Bargaining," n.d. (Folder 15: 23)
  - "The Great Depression and Its Aftermath," lecture, n.d. (Folder 15: 24)
    Notes and typescript with annotations
  - "Gustav Stolper," n.d. (Folder 15: 25)
  - "An Honest Policy Toward Rhodesia," n.d. (Folder 15: 26)
  - "In Quest of a Philosophy," n.d. (Folder 15: 27)
  - "Incomes Policy: The Weaker Mouse Trap," n.d. (Folder 15: 28)
  - "Inflation and Union Power," n.d. (Folder 15: 29)
  - Interviews, n.d.
    Typescripts
    - Canelo, Peter (Folder 15: 30)
    - Holmes, Allen (Folder 15: 31)
    - Jones, David (Folder 15: 32)
    - Levin, Fred (Folder 15: 33)
    - Meek, Paul (Folder 15: 34)
    - Meltzer, Allen (Folder 15: 35)
    - Olsen, Leif (Folder 15: 36)
    - Sternlight, Peter (Folder 15: 37)
    - Tschinkal, Sheila (Chase Manhattan) (Folder 15: 38)
  - "Irving Crystol's Speech," n.d. (Folder 15: 39)
  - "Is the UN a Threat to Peace?" n.d. (Folder 15: 40)
    Research material, typescript with annotations
  - Lecture on labor, n.d. (Folder 15: 41)
  - Lecture series, n.d.
    - "Economics and the Moral Order," Lecture I. (Folder 15: 42)
    - "Our Constitutional Inheritance," Lecture II. (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - "The Meaning of the Market," Lecture III. (Folder 16: 2)
    - "Profits and the Function of Business," Lecture IV. (Folder 16: 3)
    - "Money," Lecture V. (Folder 16: 4)
    - "Banking and Credit," Lecture VI. (Folder 16: 5)
    - "The Great Depression and Its Consequences," Lecture VII. (Folder 16: 6)
    - "The Rise of Keynesianism," Lecture VIII. (Folder 16: 7)
    - "The Role of Labor," Lecture IX. (Folder 16: 8)
    - "The U.S. in the World Economy," Lecture XI. (Folder 16: 9)
    - "The Need to Limit Government and Free the Market," Lecture XII. (Folder 16: 10)
      Holograph and typescript
    - "The Good Society," Lecture XIII. (Folder 16: 11)
  - "The Legacy of Bernard Baruch," n.d. (Folder 16: 12)
    Notes, typescript, and clippings
  - "Liberty and Order," n.d. (Folder 16: 13)
    Handwritten drafts and typescript
  - "Liberty Village and $3 Trillion Economy," n.d. (Folder 16: 14)
  - "Lunch at the Fed of New York," n.d. (Folder 16: 15)
  - "Mark Kesernick," n.d. (Folder 16: 16)
  - "Memo on Quantity Theory of Money," n.d. (Folder 16: 17)
  - "Memorandum," n.d. (Folder 16: 18)
  - "Memorandum on the Possibility of Reconciliation Between East and West," n.d. (Folder 16: 19)
  - "Message to Congress," n.d. (Folder 16: 20)
  - "The Moral Basics of Economic Progress," n.d. (Folder 16: 21)
  - "Motives, Incentives, and Expectations: A Note on the Meaning of Supply-Side Economics," n.d. (Folder 16: 22)
  - "The N.L.R.B. vs. the Courts," n.d. (Folder 16: 23)
  - "A National Economic Policy," n.d. (Folder 16: 24)
  - "Nowhere to Nowhere," n.d. (Folder 16: 25)
  - "A Plea for Common Sense," n.d. (Folder 16: 26)
  - "Poland: The Hearth and the Head," n.d. (Folder 16: 27)
  - "A Political Proposal," n.d. (Folder 16: 28)
  - "The Present Danger," n.d. (Folder 16: 29)
  - "Profits," n.d. (Folder 16: 30)
  - "Profits vs. Problems," n.d. (Folder 16: 31)
  - "Promise and Promises," n.d. (Folder 16: 32)
  - "The Promise of Voluntarism," n.d. (Folder 16: 33)
  - "Proposed Corporate Ad Campaign," n.d. (Folder 16: 34)
  - "Ralph Peters, President, Discount Corporation," n.d. (Folder 16: 35)
  - "Reaganomics Reconsidered," n.d. (Folder 16: 36)
  - "Real Threat to Nixon's Economics," n.d. (Folder 16: 37)
  - "Reflection on Hayek," n.d. (Folder 16: 38)
  - "Reform: The Road to Voluntarism," n.d. (Folder 16: 39)
  - "The Republic," n.d. (Folder 16: 40)
  - "Republicans and the Good Society," n.d. (Folder 16: 41)
  - "A Return to Gold: A Memorandum," n.d. (Folder 16: 42)
  - "Rhodesia: Ian Smith's Chickens Come Home to Roost," n.d. (Folder 16: 43)
  - "Rhodesia: The Moral Issue," n.d. (Folder 16: 44)
  - "Rhodesian Memorandum," n.d. (Folder 17: 1)
  - "The Rhodesian Sell-Out: A Lesson in U.S. Foreign Policy," n.d. (Folder 17: 2)
  - "The Right to Strike," n.d. (Folder 17: 3)
  - "The Robots Are Coming: So What," n.d. (Folder 17: 4)
  - "The Role of Business in Society," n.d. (Folder 17: 5)
  - "The Role of the White Man in Southern Africa," n.d. (Folder 17: 6)
  - "Sellout in Southwest Africa," n.d. (Folder 17: 7)
  - "South Africa in Transition," n.d. (Folder 17: 8)
  - "Southern Africa in Transition," n.d. (Folder 17: 9)